Cody Kilpatrick

Alexandria, VA, 22302 | 321-217-1718 | codykilpatrick1996@gmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

With 8 years of Navy experience between two ships and two shore facilities, I have experience in both operating and maintaining numerous sonar systems. Combining that with skills in Software Engineering in PYTHON/HTML/CSS/JavaScript gives me the tools to create products that take advantage of new technologies in order to assist sailors directly.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: Node.js, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Bulma Databases and other: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful Routing, JSON API, Unsupervised/Supervised Machine learning

Interpersonal skills: Aggressively optimistic, driven learner

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

January 2023

Ship-planner - GitHub | APP | JavaScript | Express | Node

An app that uses google OAuth to let you create groups of ships and move them around the world, great for wargamers and decision makers!

- Easy to read pages allow for viewage of critical information without having to jump around.
- Uses the MEN stack for CRUD operations with multiple resources.

December 2022

Viking Chess - GitHub | App | JavaScript

A chess-like board game where you are trying to get your king to safety against overwhelming odds. A fun game to test your strategy and planning. Easy to learn, hard to master!

- Game logic built with Javascript.
- Styled with CSS for both mobile and desktop users.
- Satisfying interactive audio makes you feel like you are using a real game board.

December 2022

Powerline fault classification - GitHub | Python | scikit-learn

Uses Supervised Machine learning models to accurately predict powerline faults to help technicians and plant managers do their jobs with more efficiency.

- Uses KNN, SVC, and Logistic Regression models.
- Achieved a f1-score average of .81 when predicting six different classes.
- Uses seaborn for data visualization.

September 2022

Eve Marketeer - GitHub | Python | Pandas

An app that pulls from the Eve online API to produce actionable results to help you and your fellow space warriors get rich!

- Interfaces with the Eve Online API to pull real-time market data.
- Uses a custom formula to determine what the best items to buy.
- Conducts data manipulation on over 500,000 data points each with more than 10 features.

EXPERIENCE

US Navy
Norfolk, VA

Commander Undersea Surveillance

04/2021-10/2022

- Responsible for the smooth transition process of hundreds of sailors within the command and transferring sailors. Relying on leveraging cross-department relationships, organizational tools and attention to detail I was able to ensure sailors were prepared for their transitions.
- Created and implemented a department training plan to increase levels of knowledge in security procedures, safety practices and overall Undersea Warfare skills.
- Coordinated with multiple contract entities in the implementation of a construction security plan for a 28 million dollar expansion project.

USS Stout 07/2018-10/2020

- Created drill packages and training materials to support multi-warfare training scenarios for the entire ship.
- Led the sonar team in the planning and prosecution of multiple real life threat submarines.
- Conducted training and interviews for all Combat Systems Officers of the Watch to ensure levels of knowledge and watchstander proficiency.
- As Combat Systems Coordinator was responsible for all anti-air engagements within 30 nm of the ship as well as assisting the Tactical Action Officer in the configuration of the Combat systems suite.

USS Laboon 12/2015-12/2018

- Conducted maintenance on the SQQ-89 Sonar Suite, ensuring mission readiness.
- Operated both active and passive sonar systems for live and simulated contacts.
- Used PC-IMAT to determine accurate sonar ranges while on two deployments to the 5th and 6th fleet AORs.

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Remote, Certificate Expected: 03/2023

• Completing 12-week coding bootcamp that involves creating four frontend, backend, and full-stack applications using focused on React, JavaScript, and Python